Cole, David L. Papers 5588
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Singer Manufacturing Company vs. International Union of Electricians, Local 227, 1952 (Box 170, Folder 6)
  7/23/52. Hearing notes regarding job duties
- Sperry vs. International Union of Electricians, Local 450, 1964 (Box 170, Folder 7)
  1964. Hearing notes regarding job discrimination; correspondence regarding arbitrability of cases
- Standard and Poor Corporation vs. Newspaper Guild, 1946 (Box 170, Folder 8)
  Hearing notes
- Strook and Company, Incorporated vs. Textile Workers Union of America, 1948 (Box 170, Folder 9)
  10/48. Hearing notes regarding holiday pay
- Tech Laboratories vs. United Electricians, Local 427, 1947-1948 (Box 170, Folder 10)
  Hearing notes regarding discharge, unsatisfactory job performance
- Texas Company vs. Bayonne Texaco Employees Association, 1948 (Box 170, Folder 11)
  Hearing notes regarding job posting
- Textile Committee vs. Textile Workers Union of America, 1945-1946 (Box 170, Folder 12-13)
  Hearing notes regarding job descriptions
- Title Guarantee and Trust Company vs. District 65, Distributive, Processing and Office Workers of America, Local 96, 1951 (Box 170, Folder 14)
  3/26/51. Hearing notes regarding bargaining unit, job duties
- Transit - Private Lines vs. Transport Workers Union of America, 1961-1963 (Box 171, Folder 1)
  Hearing notes regarding fare increases
- TransWorld Airlines vs. Airline Stewards and Stewardesses Association, 1959-1960 (Box 171, Folder 2-5)
  Arbitration Board #252. Issues: wages, crew size, bargaining unit; hearing notes, transcript, exhibit
- TransWorld Airlines vs. Airline Stewards and Stewardesses Association, 1959-1960 (Box 172, Folder 1-3)
  Arbitration Board #252. Issues: wages, crew size, bargaining unit; exhibits
- Twentieth Century Fox Corporation vs. Screen Office and Professional Employees Guild, Local 109, 1948 (Box 173, Folder 1)
  2/9/48. Issue: rates of pay; hearing notes, transcripts
- Underwood vs. International Association of Machinists, 1957 (Box 173, Folder 2)
  12/27/57. Hearing notes regarding job classification
- United Airlines vs. Airline Pilots Association, 1954 (Box 173, Folder 3-4)
  6/1/54. Hearing notes, exhibit regarding rates of pay
- United Airlines vs. Airline Pilots Association, 1962 (Box 173, Folder 5)
  5/14/62. Hearing notes regarding seniority issue
- United Parcel Service vs. International Brotherhood of Teamsters, Locals 804, 177, 138, 478, 1947 (Box 173, Folder 6)
  10/18/47. Issues: rates of pay, job classification; hearing notes, exhibit, correspondence
- United Piece Dye vs. UPD Workers, 1948-1949 (Box 173, Folder 7)
- United Service for New Americans vs. Social Service Employees Union, 1950 (Box 173, Folder 8)
  6/16/50. Hearing notes regarding seniority
- United States Rubber Company vs. United Rubber, Cork, Linoleum and Plastic Workers of America, 1946 (Box 173, Folder 9)
  11/21/46. Hearing notes regarding work week
- United States Steel Corporation vs. United Steelworkers of America, 1953 (Box 174, Folder 1)
  12/10/53. Issue: pension benefits; hearing notes, correspondence, exhibit
- Walker Manufacturing Company vs. United Auto Workers, Local 85, 1963 (Box 174, Folder 2)
  4/1/63. Hearing notes regarding retirement
- West Coast Airlines vs. Airline Pilots Association, 1965 (Box 174, Folder 3)
  9/17/65. Issue: job duties; hearing notes, correspondence
- Western Airlines, Incorporated vs. Airline Pilots Association, 1965 (Box 174, Folder 4)
  6/15/65. Issue: retirement benefits; hearing notes, exhibits, correspondence
- Western Electric Company vs. Western Electric Employees Association, 1948 (Box 175, Folder All)
  1/7/48. Issue: downgrading; transcript, exhibit, hearing notes, correspondence
- Western Electric Company vs. Western Electric Employees Association, 1948 (Box 176, Folder All)
- Western Electric Company vs. Western Electric Employees Association, 1948 (Box 177, Folder 1)
  Additional transcript
- Westinghouse Electric Corporation vs. International Union of Electricians, 1946 (Box 177, Folder 2-3)
  Issue: strike; correspondence, hearing notes
- Windalume Corporation vs. Allied Trades Council (Box 177, Folder 4)
  No date. Hearing notes regarding layoff
- Worldbestos vs. unidentified, 1947 (Box 177, Folder 5)
  8/27/47. Hearing notes regarding layoff, seniority
- World Telegram vs. Newspaper Guild of New York, 1947-1966 (Box 177, Folder 6)
  Hearing notes regarding rates of pay, fringe benefits
- Xerox Corporation vs. Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1964 (Box 177, Folder 7)
  Correspondence, agreement regarding profit sharing
- Youngs Rubber Company vs. Federal Labor Union Number 23070 of the American Federation of Labor, 1942 (Box 177, Folder 8)
  Issue: wages; correspondence, exhibit
- Yukitaka Haraguichi - Sohyo vs. unidentified, 1964 (Box 177, Folder 9)
  9/10/64. Hearing notes regarding employee rights
- Hearing notes from 1954 - 1968 under the American Federation of Labor internal disputes plan (Box 178, Folder All)
  Various unions are involved: International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Textile Workers Union of America, Communication Workers of America, United Auto Workers, etc.; none significantly dominate this section (these are chronologically arranged no-raiding agreements)
- Approximately 80 chronologically ordered, 2-3 page decisions by the `Impartial Umpire under the AFL-CIO No-Raiding Agreement', 1954- 1964 (Box 179, Folder All)
  A copy of the no-raiding agreement is included; decisions cover 10/54 - 3/64 and include decisions affecting the United Steelworkers of America, Office Employees Union, International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, International Association of Machinists, International Union of Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers; some correspondence between Cole and the AFL-CIO Executives; there is no disproportionate representation in this box, between unions or industry
- Approximately 150 decisions from 11/64 - 9/69, 1964-1969 (Box 180, Folder All)
  Chronologically ordered, affecting the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the Communication Workers of America, the Amalgamated Meat cutters and Butcher Workmen, and others; no industry or union is predominant
- Approximately 140 consecutive awards from 12/69 - 10/73, 1969-1973 (Box 181, Folder All)
  The International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, the Service Employees International Union, and the American Federation of State, County, Municipal Employees comprise the bulk of this section; also included are the Textile Workers Union of America, the International Association of Machinists, and the International Union of Operating Engineers
- Approximately 130 decisions from 12/73 - 5/77 under the AFL-CIO Internal Disputes Plan, 1973-1977 (Box 182, Folder All)
  Arranged by case number (in approximate chronological order) affecting mainly the American Federation of State, County, Municipal Employees, the Marine Engineers Benevolence Association, the Communication Workers of America, the Service Employees International Union, the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, the United Steelworkers of America, the International Union of Operating Engineers and the Graphic Artists International Union
- A partial listing of the AFL-CIO Article XX violations decided by Cole (Box 183, Folder All)
  Billing materials; examples of closed, postponed, or transferred cases; information on public sector regulations; and appealed decisions to the Executive Council
- Approximately 80 decisions from 8/66 - 2/68; 11/68 - 2/70, 1966-1970 (Box 184, Folder All)
  Affected unions include the International Association of Machinists, the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners, the United Auto Workers of America, the Retail Clerks International Union, the Communication Workers of America; no union predominates
- Approximately 60 Cole decisions from 1/70 - 2/72 under Article XX, 1970-1972 (Box 185, Folder All)
  Affecting the Textile Workers Union of America, the Communication Workers of America, the American Federation of State, County, Municipal Employees, the Service Employees International Union, the Retail Clerks International Union though no union or industry dominates this section
- Approximately 30 Cole awards from 2/72 - 10/72, 1972 (Box 185, Folder All)
  The result of disputes primarily between the Textile Workers Union of America and the International Ladies Garment Workers Union
- Approximately 40 Cole (awards) determinations (Box 185, Folder All)
  Affecting the American Federation of State, County, Municipal Employees, the Textile Workers Union of America and others though no union is predominant
- Brotherhood of Railway, Airline and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express and Station Employees vs. American Railway Supervisors Association, 1976 (Box 186, Folder 1)
  27820
- Laborers International Union of North America vs. American Federation of State, County, Municipal Employees, 1976 (Box 186, Folder 2)
  5/76, re: Florida State Services note: includes written deposition and other exhibits
- Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union vs. Retail Clerks International Association, 1976 (Box 186, Folder 3)
  6/76, re: S. Klein Department Stores and Korvettes note: includes hand written notes, affidavits, and other exhibits: application to Federal Trade Commission for transaction between S. Klein and Korvettes
- Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union (RWDSU) vs. Sheet Metal Workers International Association (SMWIA), 1973-1976 (Box 186, Folder 4)
  re: International Environmental Company note: includes letters from RWDSU and SMWIA to Mr. Cole; Mr. Cole's hand written notes; correspondence with the National Labor Relations Board; and the agreement between the International Environmental Manufacturing Company and RWDSU, AFL-CIO, the Amalgamated Workers Union, Local 88
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers vs. American Federation of State, County, Municipal Employees (AFSCME), 1974-1977 (Box 186.1, Folder 1)
  6/76, re: Public Service Board, San Antonio, Texas note: includes Mr. Cole's hand written notes; a letter to George Meany, President of the AFL-CIO, from Cole along with a copy of his determination; AFSCME's closing statement, affidavits, and a detailed description of changes in wages, fringe benefits, effective 1974 - 1977
- International Union of Operating Engineers vs. International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1976 (Box 186.1, Folder 2)
  7/76, re: King Soopers Stores note: includes note and determination from Cole to George Meany et al; Mr. Cole's hand written notes; exhibits of unfair labor practice charge (formal filing forms of the National Labor Relations Board)
- Chicago Tile Helpers Union, Local 25 vs. Tile, Marble, Terrazzo Finishers and Shopmen International Union, AFL-CIO, 1976 (Box 186.1, Folder 3)
  7/76, re: non-payment of per capita taxes note: includes decision and petition for reconsideration, explanation for reconsideration and second denial; correspondence concerning Mr. Cole's payment including Xeroxed check; Mr. Cole's hand written notes; post hearing briefs; signed agreement between both parties; attached folders of additional exhibits
- Brotherhood of Railway, Airline and Steamship Clerks, Freight Handlers, Express and Station Employees vs. American Railway Supervisors Association (ARSA) (Box 187, Folder 1)
  re: Louisville and Nashville Railroad Company note: no determination necessary (see Mr. Cole's letter to George Meany); also includes Cole's hand written notes; description of dispute; and filing of charges in letters to Meany from L.E. Dennis, ARSA International President
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers vs. International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees, etc. (Box 187, Folder 2)
  re: WPLG-TV, Miami, Florida note: includes Cole's hand written notes; copies of determination; parties' summaries of their positions; and transcript of hearing
- International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades: International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers (Box 187, Folder 3)
  re: Cummings Sign Company, Houston, Texas note: includes Cole's hand written notes; copy of agreement between parties; affidavits of employees; NO DETERMINATION, CHARGES WITHDRAWN
- Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Union vs. United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America (Box 187, Folder 4)
  re: Domino Supermarket, Bronx, New York note: includes Cole's notes; appearance list; and notification of hearing
- United Brick and Clay Workers of America vs. International Ladies Garment Workers Union (ILGWU), 1973-1976 (Box 187, Folder 5)
  re: Ralco Sewing Industries; Weather Vane Outerwear Corporation Warehouse note: includes copy of determination; Mr. Cole's hand written notes; memorandum on behalf of ILGWU; copy of agreement between parties for 1972 - 1976; letter to Mr. Cole from George Meany; agreement between ILGWU and Country Miss, Incorporated, 1973 - 1976
- Glass Container Manufacturers Institute and Glass Bottle Blowers Association, 1964 (Box 187.1, Folder 1)
  1964, re: employee discharge note: includes copy of opinion and award
- Glass Container Manufacturers Institute, Incorporated (Armstrong Cork Company) and Glass Bottle Blowers Association (Box 187.1, Folder 2)
  re: employee discharge note: includes opinion and award
- Armstrong Cork Company and Glass Bottle Blowers Association, 1964 (Box 187.1, Folder 3)
  1964, re: employee vacation pay note: includes opinion and award
- American Arbitration Association (AAA): Analytic Papers of Labor Management Institute (LMI), 1965 (Box 188, Folder 1)
  David Cole, Chairman, 1965; (contains miscellaneous correspondence regarding AAA meetings; discussions, summaries and comments on papers on collective bargaining; and two booklets on purpose of LMI)
- American Arbitration Association (AAA): Labor Management Institute (LMI), 1966 (Box 188, Folder 2)
  Arden House Conference held 11/20-23/66 in New York City attended by members of LMI for purpose of discussing research papers on new methods of collective bargaining
- American Arbitration Association (AAA): Labor Management Institute (LMI), 1963-1969 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  Advisory Committee, 1963 - 1969, David Cole, Chairman; (LMI asked by labor and management representatives to sponsor "off the record" meetings with labor and management representatives in the manufacturing sector
- American Arbitration Association (AAA): Labor Management Institute (LMI), 1964 (Box 189, Folder 2)
  Research Subcommittee, 1964; (includes correspondence regarding analytic papers to be presented)
- American Arbitration Association (AAA): Public Education Institute, 1967 (Box 189, Folder 3)
  Includes proposals for handling public employee disputes and for studying the use of computers)
- American Arbitration Association (AAA): Center for Dispute Settlement, 1969 (Box 189, Folder 4)
  LMI replaced by Center for Dispute Settlement
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 1963 (Box 190, Folder 1)
  Newspaper Industry Conference; (newspaper executives and newspaper union officials conferred and agreed to study the impact of new technology on future employment opportunities; the means of resolving or avoiding jurisdictional disputes; and the possibilities of greater use of arbitration
- American Arbitration Association (AAA): Labor Management Institute (LMI), 1964 (Box 191, Folder 1)
  Manufacturing Sector; (includes report from labor- management manufacturing sector conference 11/64; and report and booklet on collective bargaining and disputes in the construction industry)
- American Arbitration Association (AAA): Labor Management Institute (LMI), 1965 (Box 191, Folder 2)
  Manufacturing Sector; (includes report from second labor-management manufacturing sector conference, 3/65)
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 1969 (Box 191, Folder 3)
  Correspondence; (includes miscellaneous news and reports)
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 1958 (Box 192, Folder 1)
  Contains reports from regional conferences and annual meetings; and miscellaneous correspondence
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 1956-1957 (Box 192, Folder 2)
  Contains reports and minutes of the AAA Executive Committee and the Arbitration Law Committee; and miscellaneous correspondence)
- American Arbitration Association (AAA): Arbitration Law Committee, 1951 (Box 192, Folder 3)
  Includes minutes of the Arbitration Law Committee, 10/51
- American Arbitration Association (AAA): Arbitration, General (Box 192, Folder 4)
  Includes papers, notes and memoranda regarding arbitration
- American Arbitration Association (AAA) (Box 193, Folder 1)
  Minutes and notices of meetings
- American Arbitration Association (AAA) (Box 193, Folder 2)
- American Arbitration Association (AAA), 1971-1973 (Box 193, Folder 3)
  Miscellaneous
- American Arbitration Association (AAA): Labor-Management Advisory Committee, 1971 (Box 194, Folder 1-2)
- David Cole, Chairman of International Labor Organization, American Association for the United Nations, Incorporated, 1957 (Box 195, Folder 1)
- American Bar Association, Committee on Collective Bargaining, 1950 (Box 195, Folder 2)
  , 1950
- American Management Association, Personnel Conference Agenda, 1953 (Box 195, Folder 3)
  , 1953
- International Labor Organization (ILO): meeting on Industrial and Human Relations, 1956 (Box 196, Folder 1)
  , 1956; reports and documents
- International Labor Organization (ILO): assignment in Geneva, Switzerland, 1956 (Box 196, Folder 2)
  July 2-11/56; includes correspondence and list of participants
- International Labor Organization (ILO): meeting on Industrial and Human Relations, 1956 (Box 196, Folder 3)
  Geneva, Switzerland, July 2-11/56; expenses
- International Labor Organization (ILO): "Future Action in the Field of Labor-Management Relations" (Box 196, Folder 4)
  Report to ILO consultants; includes list of members of Committee of Experts
- International Labor Office (Washington, District of Columbia) (Box 196, Folder 5)
  R. Peter Straus, Director; contains correspondence with Mr. Cole
- International Labor Organization (ILO), 1964-1965 (Box 197, Folder All)
  1964 Geneva, 1965 Japan and Honolulu; contains report from fact-finding and conciliation commission on freedom of association on "the complaints of alleged infringements of trade union rights in Japan submitted to the ILO by eleven trade union organizations; record of hearings for above case; and documents for hearings and witnesses
- International Labor Organization (ILO), 1964-1965 (Box 198, Folder All)
  Hearing on trade union rights in Japan (continued from preceding folder); includes hearing notes and cultural and educational books on Japan
- International Labor Organization (ILO), 1964-1965 (Box 199, Folder All)
  Hearing on trade union rights in Japan (continued from preceding folder); includes papers by members of Committee of Experts and correspondence
- International Labor Organization (ILO), 1964-1965 (Box 200, Folder All)
  Hearing on trade union rights in Japan (continued from preceding folder); includes exhibits and newspaper clippings
- Assorted notes, correspondence, and speeches (Box 201, Folder 1)
- Speeches, 1950-1957 (Box 201, Folder 2)
- Harvard Law Review article, 1951 (Box 201.1, Folder 1)
  On the decision by the Supreme Court of New Jersey in the "Matter of the Arbitration between New Jersey Telephone and the Communication Workers of America;" article deals with how statutes are constructed
- Assorted speeches and articles, 1949 (Box 201.1, Folder 2)
  Including "Employer's Ability to Pay in Wage Determinations" and "Can Collective Bargaining be Improved?" (1949)
- University of Wisconsin, Conference on Productivity, 1949 (Box 201.1, Folder 3)
  Includes notes and proceedings and the paper "What Makes for Industrial Peace?"
- Dumont and International Union of Electricians Joint Labor-Management Educational Program (Box 201.1, Folder 4)
  Harvard Business School, the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University, Yale University, and the University of Illinois; contains speech notes
- New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations (NYSSILR) conference in Rochester, New York, 1959 (Box 202, Folder 1)
  Contains lecture notes regarding "The Arbitrator Examines the Discharge Question," and information on the NYSSILR at Cornell University
- Salzberg Seminar in American Studies, 1957 (Box 202, Folder 2)
- Conference on Government in Labor-Management Relations at the University of Pennsylvania, 1953 (Box 202, Folder 3)
  Includes "Observations on the Nature and Function of Mediation"
- Article on National Emergency Strikes, 1961-1963 (Box 202, Folder 4)
  Notes on types of third party intervention; and papers by various authors
- Internal Disputes Plan (Box 202, Folder 5)
  Book written by Phillip Taft, professor of economics, Brown University, and Mr. Cole
- Quotes and stories used for various speeches (Box 202, Folder 6)
  Notes for Conference on Automation and Employment, Kaiser Steelworkers
- University of Pennsylvania (?) (Box 202, Folder 7)
  council notes
- Dunlop Seminar, Harvard University, 1966 (Box 202, Folder 8)
  Cole's final comments
- New Jersey State Bar Association Convention, 1967 (Box 202, Folder 9)
  Topic of Mr. Cole's speech was the tenth anniversary of the Welfare and Pension Plans of the Textile Workers Union of America
- John Diebold, The Diebold Group, Incorporated, 1967 (Box 203, Folder 1)
  Mr. Cole wrote the introduction on the impact of automation and technological change on collective bargaining for the book by the Diebold Institute of Public Policy Studies
- Contains correspondence between John Diebold and Mr. Cole (Box 203, Folder 1b)
- National Academy of Arbitrators (Box 203, Folder 2)
  Includes Mr. Cole's speech "An Inductive Analysis of Labor-Management Attitudes"
- Institute of Collective Bargaining (Box 203, Folder 3)
  Contains Cole's speech "Resolving Deadlocks in Public Employment"
- S.H. Fabian's seventieth birthday (Box 203, Folder 4)
  Speech by Cole
- State Board of Education, 1968 (Box 203, Folder 5)
  Cole's speech, "Labor Relations in Public Employment," deals with strike issues
- Dedication of Sylvan Gotshal Hearing Room at the American Arbitration Association, 1969 (Box 203, Folder 6)
- AFL-CIO Federationist article (Box 203, Folder 7)
  "The Federation's No-Raiding Program"
- The Collective Bargaining Forum, 1969 (Box 204, Folder 1)
  includes Mr. Cole's speech, Resolving Deadlocks in Public Employment and other information distributed at the convention
- Practicing Law Institute (PLI), 1969 (Box 204, Folder 2)
  Includes correspondence regarding speech given by Cole for the PLI in 1969; (speech is not contained in folder)
- Eternal Light (Box 204, Folder 3)
  Television program on National Broadcasting Corporation (NBC); Mr. Cole participated in a discussion on "The Challenge of the Seventies to Labor" sponsored by the Jewish Theological Seminary of America
- Shirt Sleeve Symposium; Labor Relations in the Public Sector by the Public Employment Relations Board, 1969 (Box 204, Folder 4)
  Contains several papers by various authors concerning the use of fact-finding in dispute settlement, contains several papers by various authors concerning the use of fact-finding in dispute settlement
- Mid-West Educational Building Trades Conference, 1970 (Box 204, Folder 5)
  Cole was forced to cancel appearance; (no speech in folder)
- United Steelworkers of America Convention, 1970 (Box 204, Folder 6)
  Atlantic City; Ralph Seward (arbitrator) testimonial dinner (Cole did not attend)
- Taylor Conference at Wharton Business School, 1970 (Box 204, Folder 7)
  regarding labor relations in the seventies (co-sponsored by the American Arbitration Association)